KIA ORA, I'M JESSICA CHIU

②: +64 22 625 8411

☑: JESSICA.Q.CHIU@GMAIL.COM

ABOUT ME

People are the focus of my efforts, work, and ambition. People are constantly changing: whether it's the technology they use, their teams they work with, or even their perceptions. I hope to collaborate with you and bring my perspectives of inclusion, accessibility, and sustainability when developing strategies for vulnerabilities that perform with how people naturally change. I've developed a keen interest for learning more about the support I could bring through risk analysis, security education, and user experience - all of which I've developed an indirect experience with over the years. I would love the opportunity to be part of your team where I can both grow and help others grow too.

SKILLS

Communication

I communicate daily with users to help them through technical, banking, compliance, and trade issues. Code Club volunteering has lead me to help young students learn about software development for their projects. These experiences have developed my ability in troubleshooting issues and finding ways to communicate them in a way the user can understand - this has now also translated in communicating the strategies I develop to other teams and how I present data. My work is always adapted to be personal using clear language so that ideas can be turned into real solutions.

Teamwork

I have been involved in professional and academic projects which have taught me the value of developing a strong team dynamic. Through my roles, I've learned the importance of collaboration to promote a supportive work culture and to provide the best experience for our users. I believe in cultivating an environment where everyone is comfortable and safe, where sharing their ideas and asking questions is encouraged because this is how I also grew to develop my own skills.

Active Learner

I am diligent with my tasks and would never turn down an opportunity to grow my knowledge. I am always excited to pick up new skills to provide insight and solutions the best I can. While I might not have all the answers, I'll have the motivation to learn how to find them.

WORK EXPERIENCE

OPERATIONS ANALYST

Hatch | 2021 - Present

- Developing solutions for customer onboarding processes with AML requirements
- Execution of customer onboarding individual and trust accounts: collection of customer due diligence and know your customer information for account verification
- Banking support and risk analysis: reconciliation of foreign exchange revenue, booking foreign exchange trades, reconciling and verifying transactions
- Reviewing and updating procedure documents for the Operations and Support teams, reporting on operational issues and banking statistics

CUSTOMER SUCCESS SPECIALIST

Hatch | 2020 - 2021

- Quickly built up knowledge and experience within a financial start-up environment. Improved the contact and onboarding process for customers and the deposit process with customer due diligence checks with insight from customer feedback and statistics.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT REPRESENTATIVE

Trade Me | 2018 - 2020

- Site Functionality and Trade Support Team. Consistently met support objectives to the highest tier standard. 95% customer satisfaction feedback rating (85% average), and a 99.62% 6-Week Rolling average internally marked quality score. Reflecting the efforts I put into problem solving to understand the user's issue and provide a personal experience that took into account all the factors of the situation.
- Worked responsibly to comply with security and risk standards which helped me build an interest PCI DSS compliant, safely handling payment transactions, and retaining confidential information which may affect company stakeholders.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

VICTORIA UNIVERSITY OF WELLINGTON // TE HERENGA WAKA

BCom, major in Information Systems, minor in Management, specialisation in IT Solutions \mid 2017 - 2019

Coursework: Digital Strategy, Enterprise Architecture, Management of IT Projects, Systems Analysis, Business Analytics, Application Development, UX Design, Statistics

ACG YOOBEE SCHOOL OF DESIGN

STAR Funded Short Courses | 2014 - 2015 Web Design, Graphic Design, Game Design

WELLINGTON GIRLS' COLLEGE

NCEA Level 1, 2, 3 | 2011 - 2015

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT AND VOLUNTEERING

GOOGLE ONLINE COURSES

Online Courses | 2018, 2020, 2021

System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services, Technical Support Fundamentals, The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking, and Google Digital Unlocked Courses

AWS CERTIFICATION SCHOLARSHIP

A Cloud Guru in partnership with Women Who Code | 2018

CODE CLUB AOTEAROA/SHE CAN CODE VOLUNTEER

Education Support | 2018-2020

Helping primary and secondary school students work on STEM projects. Providing support through troubleshooting, marking, and encouragement in learning.